Bernard Murphy

753 Main Boulevard, Providence, RI 08642 b.rnurphy@nnyemail.com (135) 531-1357

Seasoned master technician with 11 + years' experience providing high-quality services to domestic vehicle owners in busy automotive garages. Outstanding technical knowledge with a commitment to exploring and utilizing up-to-date technologies. Strong leadership and communication skills with a proven aptitude for training and developing junior technicians.

Key Skills

- Brake repair and maintenance
- Computer diagnostics
- Hydraulics
- Customer service
- Staff education and management

Professional Experience

Master Automotive Technician

Pep Boys, Providence, RI I September 2017 - Present

- Explain complex technical problems and propose solutions clearly to customers, receiving a consistent 5-star average rating throughout employment
- Seek continuous education to ensure up-to-date knowledge of emerging technologies and communicate acquired information to colleagues
- Leverage advanced computer systems to diagnose brake and hydraulic problems and generate appropriate repair plans, acting as an escalation point for the most complex issues
- Supervise and deploy up to 15 general technicians and provide support, achieving a 91% staff retention rate in 2020

Automotive Technician

Firestone Complete Auto Care, Providence, RI [July 2009 - September 2017

- Performed research on particular vehicles and parts before appointments, improving operational efficiency by 65% over three years
- Carried out vehicle testing and safety checks and diagnosed faults, using findings to suggest repair and maintenance work
- Created detailed estimates for customers with 98%+ accuracy throughout employment
- Maintained a hygienic, hazard-free working environment and reported any safety concerns to senior management

Education

Associate of Science in Automotive Technology

New England Institute of Technology, East Greenwich, RI September 2007 - June 2009